hmed Ezzat

□+20 112 735 3617 | 🗷 ah.ezzat.mh@gmail.com | 🖸 Rathetsu | 🛅 AhmedEzzatMuh

Summary.

An impassioned Software Engineer with more than three years of professional experience. Well-versed in Mathematics and Applied Statistics. Highly passionate about Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Computer Vision and Theoretical CS. Mentored aspiring engineers across a wide variety of CS topics and aided them to build a strong skill-set and deep understanding of the covered topics. Seeking to extend and apply my domain of knowledge to exciting problem spaces and help more people fall in love with Computer Science.

Experience __

Mobile Development Lead

Sharjah, UAE

NABTA HEALTH LTD.

July 2021 - Present

- · Worked on improving the app's chat-bot to be Al-powered for diagnosing various health conditions as well as recommending products that match the user's interests and goals.
- Worked on CI/CD scripting and app store publishing.
- Developed an NFC temperature sensor driver SDK for native Android using Java.
- · Built a self-contained library for analyzing and predicting users' ovulation windows given their daily temperature readings.
- · Developed a mechanism to give different users different roles where each corresponds to a certain set of permissions. Used Spring Security.
- Conducted the technical interviews for internship candidates as well as permanent positions.

Private Tutor

TEACHING AN INTRO TO COMPUTER SCIENCE USING PYTHON

Cairo, Egypt June 2022 - Present

- Course Contents: Branching, Iteration, String Manipulation, Functions, Recursion, Debugging, OOP, Program Efficiency and others
- Developed teaching materials, such as slides, problem-sets, and recitations.
- Conducted weekly sessions on the course materials along with grading student submissions.
- Assessed students progress throughout tutoring sessions.
- · Helped students better understand conceptual nuances and held problem-set discussions with students to help fill the gaps.

Software Engineer Sharjah, UAE

NABTA HEALTH LTD.

- Developed many React Native components corresponding to primary features.
- Developed several REST client-side web-service interfaces.
- Developed a complete *Payment System* for the Nabta App.
- Participated in code review
- · Contributed to writing an FSM chat-bot for guiding users through numerous processes inside the Nabta app.

Software Engineering Intern

Shariah, UAE

June 2020 - July 2021

NABTA HEALTH LTD. Mar 2020 - June 2020

- Resolved various bugs/issues in the Nabta App.
- Developed multiple registration features and was responsible for both the server-side & the client-side implementations.
- Contributed to integrating an Order Management System to ship Nabta products.

Software Engineering Intern

Alexandria, Egypt

NAHR DEVELOPMENT

June 2019 - Sep 2019

- Developed multiple components for an e-commerce mobile application using Xamarin.
- Contributed to deploying multiple projects to production.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Java, Groovy, Go, C#, SQL, Verilog

Mobile Development React Native, Redux, Native Android, Flutter, Xamarin

Web Development Django, Flask, Node, Express, Grails, Spring Security, Redux, React.js, Next.js, HTML5, LESS, SASS

Software & Libraries VS Code, Android Studio, Git, Docker, UNIX, LaTeX, TensorFlow, Keras, Pandas, PyTorch

Projects.

Contacts App Android/Java

ANDROID ARCHITECTURE PRACTICE

 A simple CRUD Android Contacts App that allows you to manage your Contacts. It lets you view all the Contacts as a list, Add, Update, Delete and View the Contact Details. It was done as practice on implementing the MVC and MVVM android architectures.

Sudoku Game Python

PERSONAL PROJECT

• A Sudoku game a solver that features a simple UI and is using the backtracking algorithm.

LTI System Simulator Python

SYSTEM ANALYSIS COURSE PROJECT

- A simulator that computes and visualizes the output of a 'linear time invariant' system.
- Uses NumPy, Matplotlib and Tkinter for GUI and features advanced applied mathematics.

Collaborative Whiteboard Node.js, Express and React PERSONAL PROJECT • A multi-user whiteboard that syncs all edits in real-time wired with web sockets. **Arithmetic Chat-bot** C++ PERSONAL PROJECT • An interactive chat-bot that does arithmetic operations when prompted by the user. **Linear Systems Solver** (++ PERSONAL PROJECT • A console program that solves systems of linear equations for any number of variables. • The solving algorithm uses Gaussian Elimination and Cramer's Method. Implemented multi-threading to optimize solving for high number of variables. **Awards & Activities** ACADEMIC & PROFESSIONAL **Tutor**, Held sessions to teach the mobile development team members the intricacies of a library I wrote. 2022 Nabta Health, UAE 2020 Intern of the Month, Two times in three month during my internship with the company Nabta Health, UAE 2019 1st Place, Most efficient LTI System Simulator - System Analysis Course - Ain Shams University Cairo, Egypt EXTRACURRICULAR 2021 **4th Place**, Dell's $C(4F)_2$ Artificial Intelligence Hackathon Egypt 2020 Contestant, ACM Egyptian Collegiate Programming Contest (ECPC) Alexandria, Egypt 2020 Finalist, ACM ECPC Local Qualifiers (ASUCPC) Cairo, Egypt 2020 **2nd Place**. Enactus's Youth Empowerment Hackathon Giza, Egypt Contestant, ACM Egyptian Collegiate Programming Contest (ECPC) 2019 Alexandria, Egypt Finalist, ACM ECPC Local Qualifiers (ASUCPC) 2019 Cairo, Egypt Tutor, SefrWahed's Algorithms and Problem Solving Workshop Cairo, Egypt

Education

Ain Shams University

B.Sc. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Cairo, Egypt

2016 - 2021

Languages .

 $- \bullet$ Arabic (mother tongue) $- \bullet$ English (near-native) $- \bullet$ German (A1-certified)